<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Tim Mastny</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Tim Mastny</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Meta-Analysis of Periodization in Strength Training</title>
      <link>/blog/bayesian-meta-analysis-periodization-brms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/bayesian-meta-analysis-periodization-brms/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Data Cleaning My Methodology Future Work   Introduction Greg Nuckols, a powerlifting coach, graduate student, and all around smart guy just did an excellent meta-analytic study on periodization methods in strength training on his website Strong By Science. If your not sure what periodization (or strength training) is, I would encourage you to read Greg’s article and explore his website. In this blog post I would like to focus on the statistical content of Greg’s article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidying Messy Spreadsheets</title>
      <link>/blog/tidying-messy-spreadsheets-dplyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tidying-messy-spreadsheets-dplyr/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Why Tidy? The Data Follow Along Cleaning Final Product Conclusion   Introduction I want this post to be an introduction to cleaning and preparing a messy spreadsheet as part of a data science pipeline. Instead of presenting a final product, I’d like to emphasize exploration as a natural part of tidying. My approach will follow Hadley Wickham’s tidy data principles outlined in his tidy data paper. At the end, our data should satisfy these three characteristics:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MRP Using brms and tidybayes</title>
      <link>/blog/multilevel-mrp-tidybayes-brms-stan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/multilevel-mrp-tidybayes-brms-stan/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The Data Tidying Variables Tidying Poststratification  Model 1: Disaggragation Model 2: Maximum Likelihood Multilevel Model Model 3: Full Bayesian Model Model Comparisons   Introduction In the last post I wrote the “MRP Primer” Primer studying the p part of MRP: poststratification. This post explores the actual MRP Primer by Jonathan Kastellec. Jonathan and his coauthors wrote this excellent tutorial on Multilevel Regression and Poststratification (MRP) using r-base and arm/lme4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poststratification Primer with dplyr</title>
      <link>/blog/poststratification-with-dplyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/poststratification-with-dplyr/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Another example The Total Statistic The Total and Weighted Averaging  Conclusion   Introduction This post will introduce poststartification: the process of correcting non-representative samples to better reflect the actual population proportions. There are some excellent resources to learn about multilevel regression and poststratification (MRP or Mister P), but most are heavy on multilevel regression and light on poststratification.
My next blog post will dive into the MRP Primer by Jonathan Kastellec using tools such as Stan, brms, and tidybayes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/</guid>
      <description> periodization-meta-analysis </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>